He's never been cooler.
Die Another Day is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by Lee Tamahori.
James Bond is sent to investigate the connection between a North Korean terrorist and a
diamond mogul, who is funding the development of an international space weapon.
James Bond, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Jinx, played by Halle Berry.
Gustav Graves, played by Toby Stephens.
Miranda Frost, played by Rosamund Pike.
Zao, played by Rick Yune.
M, played by Judi Dench.
Die Another Day is a 2002 action spy film and the twentieth film in
the James Bond series produced by Eon Productions.
It was directed by Lee Tamahori, produced by Michael G.
Wilson and Barbara Broccoli, and written by Neal Purvis and Robert Wade.
The fourth and final film starring Pierce Brosnan as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond, it was also the
only film to feature John Cleese as Q, and the last with Samantha Bond as Miss Moneypenny.
It is also the first film since Live and Let Die (1973) not to feature
Desmond Llewelyn as Q as he died three years earlier.
Halle Berry co-stars as Bond girl and NSA agent Jinx.
In the film, Bond attempts to locate a traitor in British intelligence who betrayed him and a British
billionaire who is later revealed to be connected to a North Korean operative who Bond seemingly killed.
It is an original story, although it takes influence from Bond creator Ian Fleming's novels Moonraker
(1955) and The Man with the Golden Gun (1965), as well as Kingsley Amis's novel, Colonel Sun.
The title song was performed by Madonna.
Die Another Day was released on 20 November 2002 internationally by 20th Century Fox
and 22 November 2002 in the United States by MGM Distribution Co.
under the Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer label.
It marked the James Bond franchise's 40th anniversary.
The film includes references to each of the preceding films.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised Tamahori's direction, but
criticised the reliance on CGI, product placement, the story and the villain.
Nevertheless, the film was a box-office success with it grossing $432 million
worldwide, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2002.
The next film in the series, Casino Royale, was released in November 2006, which also served
as a reboot of the franchise with Daniel Craig replacing Brosnan as Bond.
The film explores themes of post-traumatic stress disorder
(ptsd), espionage, spy, demonstration, fencing.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.